Guide to the David Allee papers, 1960-2005.
Allee, David papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
David Allee papers, 1960-2005.
21-43-3276
David J. Allee
20 cubic ft.
Correspondence, memoranda, and subject files
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, memoranda, subject files and reports concerning Allee's work with Resource Economics, Public Policy, and Water Quality related concerns, and the New York State Main Street Alliance, the Adirondack Research Consortium, Cornell's Water Resources and Marine Sciences Center, and Community and Rural Development Institute, and other economic development programs.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Resource Economics and the leader of the Cornell Local Government Program, New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, Dept. of Applied Economics and Management.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, memoranda, subject files and reports concerning Allee's work with Resource Economics, Public Policy, and Water Quality related concerns, and the New York State Main Street Alliance, the Adirondack Research Consortium, Cornell's Water Resources and Marine Sciences Center, and Community and Rural Development Institute, and other economic development programs.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Allee, David J.; Adirondack Research Consortium.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University. Local Government Program.; Cornell University. Community and Rural Development Institute.; Cornell University. Water Resources and Marine Sciences Center.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences.Dept. of Applied Economics and Management.; New York State Main Street Alliance.
Subjects:
Water quality management.; Water--Pollution.
Form and Genre Terms:
Videotapes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Publications, 1960-2000
  - Publications, 1960's (Box 1)
  - Publications, 1970's (Box 2)
  - Publications, 1980's (Box 3)
  - Various Publications and Course Material (Box 4)
- Series II: Proposals and Subject Files, 1960-2005
  - Proposals and Subject Files, 1980's-2001 (Box 5)
  - New York Main Street Alliance (NYMSA), 1991-2002 (Box 6)
  - National Association of Management and Technical Assistance Centers (NAMTAC) and Economic Development Administration (EDA), 1991-1998; Local Government Program (LGP), 1972-1988; Catskill Watershed Corp., 1998le files; Initiatives, 1985-1988 1988 (Box 7)
  - EDA/NAMTAC, 1995-2000 (Box 8)
  - NYMSA, 1992-2000; Business Retention and Expansion (BRE), 1992-1997; EDA/NAMTAC, 1993-1994, 2000 (Box 9)
  - Housing and Dining Committees, 1967-1969; Institute for Water Resources (IWR), 1970-1971; American Water Resources Association (AWRA), 1997-2002; Watersheds, 1978-1992, 1967-1992 (Box 10)
  - Watersheds and Septic: Subject files, Adirondack Park Agency, Cayuga Network, Keuka Lake, Cayuga Lake, Government Policy Education Project Workshop (GPEP), 1990-1999 (Box 11)
  - New York Water Quality, Superfund Amendments and the Reauthorization Act (SARA), 1990-1991; Lake Champlain, 1993-1994; Connecticut River, Delaware River Basin, Mad River, Hudson River; Septic Information, 1999-2000, 1990-2000 (Box 12)
  - Septics: Geographic Files-Cayuga County, Syracuse, Binghamton, etc; Subject Files, 1998-1999 (Box 13)
  - Septics: papers and correspondence, 1999-2001; Watersheds: Federation of Lake Associations (FOLA) conference, notes, correspondence, 1998-2001 (Box 14)
  - Cayuga Lake: Hector Land Use Area, 1945, 1962, 1983; Agricultural Economics 350, Field Trip Notes; Water Supply Rules, 1988-1989; Cayuga Lake Basin and Oswego Basin studies, 1965-1973; Bell Station, 1969-1975; Cayuga Station, 1977 Regional Lake Boards, 1970-1974, 1945-1989 (Box 15)
  - Municipal Information Exchange (MUNEX), 1996-1998; SVS and Federation; Risk Management Institute, 1981-1991; Pavement of local roads, 1985-1995; Local Governments and taxes, 1976, 1996; Yard Waste, composting, landfills, education, 1988-1993; Resource Economics proposals, 1970-1985, 1970-1998 (Box 16)
  - Land use and water Quality, risk assessment and groundwater protection strategies, research papers, 1981-1989 (Box 17)
  - Cornell Local Government Program (CLGP), 1983-2000; Community and Rural Development Institute (CaRDI), 1997-1998; Honduras, "Disaster Recovery and Mitigation" 1999, Higher Education for Development Partnership with Zamorano; Cornell Economic Renewal (CER), 1998-2002; Association of Cornell Cooperative Extension Educators (ACCEE), 1998-2000, 1970-2000 (Box 18)
  - ACCEE, 2001; CER, 1999-2000; Southold Studies, land values, local economy and planning, 1965-1967, 1999-2001 (Box 19)
  - Southold, 1965-1967; Cayuga Lake, 1961-1969; Class Notes: Agricultural Economics 652/Natural Resources 493 Land Economics Problems, CEE 529 Water Resource Policy; Awards and Plaques, 1965-1996 (Box 20)
- Series III: Videotapes
  - Regional and Local Economic Outlook: The Impact on Housing and Households, June 18, 1991; V-6250-6251 (Box 21)
  - Non-Point Source Pollution Prevention, April 13, 1994; V-6252-6253 (Box 21)
  - Business Retention Expansion in New York State-Cornell Cooperative Extension Network Satellite In-Service, April 1994; V-6254 (Box 21)
  - Schuyler Scope, V-6255 (Box 21)
  - Economic Vitality-Cornell Cooperative Extension Network Satellite, V-6256 (Box 21)
  - Well, Here's What the Experts Think, V-6257 (Box 21)
  - Understanding and Maintaining Alternative On-Site Sewage Disposal Systems-produced by Snohomish Health District, Thurston County Environmental Health Division; Puget Sound Water Quality Authority, April 1994; V-6258 (Box 21)